In this video, I'll be showing you how to deploy the company portal to your devices using Microsoft Intune.
So if you are working as an IT system administrator, definitely you will not want your users to be downloading the company portal from Microsoft Store.
You want to deploy the others app using config manager or Microsoft Intune.
Well, in this video, we're going to be focusing on how to deploy the company portal using Microsoft Intune.
So first of all, what you want to do is the phone and you want to go to your business store.microsoft.com.
And from there, you can now go to settings.
And from settings, you would definitely want to go to manage.
And then here you can see we have shop.
And that's the moment you can see shopping experience is the shoes offline app.
But the fault, this is set to off.
So you want to at least set it to on.
At that setting it to on, then you go to your set, the store, and then type company portal.
And here we need to just click on the set button.
By clicking it, you can see shoes results for company portal.
And here we go. You can see we have a company portal, it says it's exactly free.
So I just click on that.
And right now you can see that it says license type is online.
So it is very, very, very important because you want to actually change this to offline.
Because the company portal is actually delivered through the Microsoft Store.
So Microsoft Store apps are delivered from the Microsoft Store online.
But I'll tell it deploys using config manager or your Microsoft Intune.
You definitely want to download the offline portal.
So now we have the option offline and then we can now click manage.
So by clicking manage, you can see we have different options here.
You can see we can't really select Windows 10 or the devices, which is Windows 10 and above.
And then you can see we have the fashion, you want to go for the latest, the highest fashion.
And the architecture, you can see we have different fashion as well.
So what I want to select, they see the four beats because my Windows operating system
or since the four beats.
And then the download app is going to be in English.
I'm going to leave that for the United States.
But mind you, by selecting that, you can see we have different download here.
First of all, we have the app himself, it's a download package.
That's the, we got to click download.
And when I scroll down, you can see we have some other download.
We also need to download here.
You can see it's about one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
So now we need to download about eight apps.
So if I click download, you can see it's going to download it.
And then that's the Microsoft company portal with a required key.
And then from there on, we cannot decide to just click download and generate license.
And this all will be actually downloaded to your download folder.
So what actually did is actually copy all the other download files here to the separate folder I created.
You can see we have, for example, how the AWPX bundle file JSON being an APPX.
So if I download download this file, just try and put all this file together.
One folder.
And then let's go to Microsoft Intion.
From your Microsoft Intion, you want to go to apps.
And from your apps, you want to go to all apps.
So here you can see I've already downloaded it and deployed to my devices.
But I just want to show you how to do it.
You should in case you are doing it for the first time.
So what you want to do is to click the add.
And here we go to click select.
In the select, we're going to actually select the line of business app.
So just click on that.
And then you can see all the different apps options we can't really install through the line of business app.
So just click select.
And now we want to select our app package file.
So click on select our package file.
And then it says our package file.
And then you can see if you go to click there, you can see all the some of the apps.
I was giving you some info.
But let me just click on this no file select text.
No file choosing.
Let me just click on that folder.
And it's going to take me to my folder.
Definitely maybe to a different folder.
But then you can't browse to the folder where all your files are.
Look at it, look at it.
So first of all, I want to actually select this file.
And then click open as the app, export the file, and then click open.
But we can open.
You can see it says select dependency app file.
It is very, very important.
You see that you select the dependency app file.
Because without the dependency app file, the installation will definitely fill.
So what you need to do right now is to click on this for that game.
And now we can now select just with control a, and then click open.
You can see all the files have just been inserted.
And then we can now click OK.
By clicking OK, you can see here we have the company.
Well, the name of the Microsoft company portal description.
You can totally change the description.
But at this moment, let me just try to just add the file into it.
Because I've already created one before now.
And then here we can enter some extra information.
Well, it says, show this as a featured app in a company portal.
Well, you can actually show this as a featured app.
Because you're totally trying to install it.
Right now both can centrally show it.
But at the same time, we are trying to install it for the first time.
I'm going to use as the file.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to leave it just like this.
And the category we can't set to actually choose the category.
Let me just leave this for company management.
And then we can now click Nest.
So here it says, we can actually assign this to all devices.
But best practices are totally to deploy to just a group of device.
And then from there, you cannot check.
If, for example, the file is properly downloaded and installed on another file
before you now distribute it to all devices worldwide.
But the best you want to do is allocate a security group.
I'm a security group.
You cannot just decide to go and then select.
For example, I can, okay, I have a Windows 11 device.
Let me just select Windows 10 for now and then click select.
And then we can now decide to just click Nest.
Okay, here you can actually just see all the information.
You can check if all is properly configured.
You see your required or my, actually, select the group called all Windows 10.
And then we can now click Create.
So by clicking Create, you can see it's going to actually, since the application's created.
And now what is going to happen is going to actually import those files into,
it's going to upload the Microsoft portal into your, into Intune.
It's going to take some few minutes.
You can see we have a sys file that I've been uploaded right now.
And then after that, the file will now be distributed to your Windows.
10 or Windows 11 device.
But I want to give you some information because distributing this file to this device
may take some time.
But what we can't really do is a full and totally speed,
speed of the device, that the virus is as far as quick as possible.
If, for example, this has been completed, we can now go to all the, to devices.
Let me just select all devices.
And here we, for example, let's say we have our Windows 10 device.
You can see it's called Manage.
And then I can just select this device.
Going to sync.
What I'm going to do is I'm what I totally sync.
Here I'm going to click Sync.
So by sync, click Sync.
It's going to sync every policy, compliance policy, security policies, deployment.
I made it from Intune to that device.
So by clicking Sync, it says Intune will attempt to check with this device.
It's successful to sync or sync or action or policies to the device.
I can then say yes.
And then here we go.
It will now start syncing L.
Pre-info from my Intune to that device.
And now if I go to, for example, let me just go to my Windows 10.
There's a Windows 11 device.
Let me go to this Windows 10.
And if I if you go to Windows 10, after some time, you're going to see
that the CompNet portal has been installed on this device.
Here we can see I've already deployed.
You can see it says New.
And if I go back again to my Windows 11, I think I have the same.
Here you can see we have our CompNet portal recently added.
But totally fasten everything as well from your Windows 10 or Windows 11 device.
Let me just use Windows 10 as an example.
We can go to Settings.
And from Settings, we can go to Account.
And on account, we can now go to Access work or school.
So from Access work or school, you can see we have Connected to health,
global domain.
Here I want to click on Info.
And my click on Info, it gives me the option that will click Sync.
So here the device sync status.
My clicking Sync is good to actually sync with Microsoft Intune.
And then check all the policies and applications here you can see.
This is a company portal seceded Microsoft Intune Management extension.
And first of all, it is also completed.
I can see some of the policies that have been deployed to this device.
So if I click Sync, it will now try to sync my Microsoft Intune and Cloud
and download all these policies, the policies or compliance policies
and application that has been deployed to this device.
This is how you deploy Microsoft in the company portal to your Windows 10 or Windows 11 devices using Microsoft Intune.